The Other House
While I was hanging up the laundry, the phone rang.
（幸田(こうだ)の妻）
洗濯物を干していたら電話が鳴った
受話器を取ったら
“もしもし”と細い声がして—
When I picked up the receiver, a weak voice said, "Hello?"
“今 大丈夫ですか”と
言うから—
He continued, "Is now a good time?"
I thought it was that scam that's been in the news where they pretend to be family and ask for money, so I raised my guard,
“ああ これが
よくニュースで言ってる—”
“オレオレ詐欺か”と身構えたら…
but then the voice said, "It's been a while. It's Rei."
“お久しぶりです　零(れい)です”と
いう声が聞こえてきた
（零）こんにちは
Hello.
（幸田の妻）声の持ち主は—
The owner of the voice was a boy who had lived in my home up until a few years ago.
数年前まで
我が家で預かっていた男の子だった
Long time no see, Tarou.
（零）
タロウ 久しぶり　元気だったか？
How have you been?
Tarou's become an old man, huh?
（幸田の妻）タロウ
おじいちゃんになったでしょう
Lately all he does is sleep there.
最近は いつも
ここで寝てばかりなのよ
Is that right, Tarou?
そっか タロウ
（鳴き声）
歩(あゆむ)君は元気ですか？　香子(きょうこ)さんも
How is Ayumu doing?
And Kyouko?
Ayumu is going to a prep school,
and I guess you'd say Kyouko is a temp worker.
歩は今 予備校で—
香子は 派遣っていうのかしら
あちこち行ってるわ
She works here and there.
（幸田の妻）
そう答えながら 私は この子が—
As I answered him, I was relieved that he came to visit when I was alone.
私１人のときに来てくれたことに
ホッとしていた
香子と歩がいたら 一瞬で また
この居間は 凍りついていただろう
If Kyouko and Ayumu were here,
this living room would've become cold in an instant.
あのころみたいに…
Just like it did back then.
（零）あの…　これ
Um, these are sweets from a shop run by
a family that's been helping me a lot lately.
最近 よくお世話になってる
和菓子屋さんのお菓子です
I hope you don't mind.
良かったら
（幸田の妻）
そう この家では もう—
That's right.
No one speaks his name anymore in this house.
誰も
この子の名を口に出す者はない
I apologize for not being able to visit in a long time.
（零）長いこと ちゃんと挨拶に
来られないで すみませんでした
（幸田の妻）心配したわ
全然 顔も見せないんだもの
"I was worried about you since you never came by."
I was going to say that, but I stopped myself.
…と言おうと思って 口をつぐんだ
この子は 全部 分かっていて—
This boy understood everything
and did us a favor by staying away.
うちに来ないでいてくれたのだ
そして—
As I awkwardly sat with him, unable to look him in the eyes,
気まずくて 目を合わせられないで
座っている私と—
向かい合ってくれている
he remained across from me.
So mellow...
柔らかく…　そうだ　柔らかい
That's it. Mellow.
この子は
随分と雰囲気が柔らかくなった
He seems much more mellow now.
大人になった
He's become an adult.
歩と同じ年？　信じられない
Is he the same age as Ayumu?
I can't believe it.
My son hasn't changed.
うちの子は
まだ変わらず子供のままなのに
He's still a child.
I realized my children were no match for him at a fairly early stage.
うちの子たちが彼にかなわないのは
わりと早い段階で気がついた
It wasn't a complicated situation.
単純な話だ
Anyone could see that the amount
of practice he did was unbelievable.
はた目にも 明らかに
練習量がケタ違いだったのだ
それでも 彼に負けたくないのなら
彼より更に練習しないと始まらない
But if they didn't want to lose to him,
they would have to practice even more than he did.
It was a simple answer.
簡単な答えだった
However, could they do it?
だが しかし できるかといえば
できなかったのだ
No, they couldn't.
正論を
粛々と体現していく彼を前に—
He silently embodied sound reasoning,
and in his presence,
their weakness made them lose their equilibrium,
うちの子たちは
自分の弱さに心を乱し—
and they collapsed into pieces.
粉々に崩れていった
私は 自分の子供たちに反発され
戸惑い—
When my own children turned against me, I was lost,
主人は ただ黙って それを見ていた
and my husband silently watched it all unfold.
"People who need other people to motivate them will eventually come up against a brick wall."
“やる気を他人に出させて
もらわないといけない人間は—”
“どっちにしても
いずれ行き詰まる”
That was his view.
それが主人の持論だった
弱い自分を直視できず
手の届く楽しさに のみ込まれ—
Unable to reckon with how weak they'd become,
they became caught up in whatever fun things were within reach.
One day, Ayumu declared,
"Being able to make an effort is a talent too!"
ある日 “だって
努力できるのも才能じゃん”
…と言い放った歩の言葉に—
“ハハッ”と 夫は笑った
In reply, my husband just chuckled.
あれが多分 あの人が—
I think that was the moment he gave up on
Ayumu becoming a professional shogi player.
棋士としての歩を
見限った瞬間だったのだろう
あの子を見ていて
思い知らされたのは—
After spending time around that boy,
they realized that people who wanted to make it had to pursue their goal to the same extent as he did.
たどりつきたい場所を
持ってしまった人間というのは—
ここまで突き詰めないと
いけないのかということだった
“なりたいものに
なれる人間なんて—”
I always thought that only a small handful
of people can become what they want to be,
“ほんのひと握りの
人だけなのだから”と—
and I never thought about what you have to do to achieve that,
どうやったらなれるかも
考えずに来た私にとって—
so that boy's situation was a dreary weight on my chest.
あの子の姿は
胸にモヤモヤと重かった
そして ある日
やっと思い至ったのだ
And then one day, I finally came to a realization.
自分の夫も
あの子と同じような子供時代を—
My husband had a similar childhood as that boy.
歩んできた人間であるということに
分かっているようで
本当には分かっていなかった
I thought I understood, but I really didn't.
将棋というものを通して見れば—
Looking past shogi,
この家の中で 主人にとって
いちばん分かり合える人間は—
out of all the people in the house, the person my husband related to the most wasn't a family member,
家族ではなく あの子だったのだ
but that boy.
彼は 一心に将棋に打ち込み
勉強も黙々とこなし—
He was wholeheartedly dedicated to shogi,
silently studied and did homework,
and even helped out around the house.
家のことも手伝った
本当にいい子だった
He really was a good boy.
それが ますます
うちの子２人を苦しめた
But that made my children suffer all the more.
どうして この子は
こんなにもいい子なんだろう
Why is he such a good boy?
Why didn't my children turn out like that?
なんで うちの子は こういうふうに
育たなかったんだろう
What were the differences between the way his mother raised him and how I raised my kids?
彼の母親と 私の育て方は
どこが違ったんだろう
Did I fail in raising my children?
私は 子育てに失敗したのかな
Or is he just playing the role of a "good boy" as best he can since he's a freeloader?
彼は居候だから—
ここにいるために 一生懸命
“いい子”を演じているのかな
ホントは 私たちのこと
バカにしてるんじゃないのかな…
Maybe he's laughing at us behind our backs.
いいえ
No.
違う
That's wrong.
彼は… 零は ただ—
He was...
Rei actually was...
ただ本当にいい子だった
just a really good boy.
子供たちも そして私も—
My children understood that, and so did I.
And yet we took advantage of him.
それを分かっていて
零に甘えたのだ
We took advantage, pushed him away, treated him poorly,
甘えて 突き放して
ぞんざいに扱って—
and didn't make him feel at home.
彼に居場所を与えなかった
そして 彼は…
And so he felt like...
"The longer I'm around, the more strained everyone's relationships will become."
自分がいると みんなが
どんどんギクシャクしていくから…
だけど
それすら口に出すこともせずに—
But he didn't even say that.
静かに家を出ていった
He just quietly left.
５時の鐘が流れると
零は席を立った
When the five o'clock bell rang out, Rei got up from his chair.
そして “それじゃ”と言ったあと
結びの言葉が探せずに…
He said goodbye and skipped any other closing remarks,
“また来ます”と言った
apart from, "I'll come again."
“また来てね”と 私も答えた
"Yes, please do come again," I answered.
だって ほかに何て言えたろう
What else could I possibly say?
（零）じゃあな タロウ
See you, Tarou.
長生きしてな
Live a long life, okay?
（零）元気でな
Take care.
（幸田の妻）零が帰って
私は台所で 夕飯の支度を始めた
After Rei left, I started preparing dinner in the kitchen like I always did.
いつものとおりに
誰も連絡をよこさなくても
毎日 私は ここに立つ
Even if no one calls me, I stand here every day.
ご飯を作って みんなを待つ
I make dinner and wait for everyone.
その晩 私は夢を見た
That night, I had a dream.
零が
ホントの私の子供であった夢だった
In it, Rei really was my son.
ホントの子供になった彼は—
Now that he was my son, Rei was sprawled out in the living room, eating junk food, watching TV,
居間で だらしなく寝そべって
お菓子を食べ テレビを見—
and when I told him to go to bed, he retorted, "I don't wanna!"
“早く寝なさい”と言う私に
“うるさいなぁ”と口答えをした
私は “な〜んだ　これじゃ
歩や香子と同じじゃないか”
I thought to myself, "Look at that!
He's the same as Ayumu and Kyouko."
…と がっかりしながら—
I was disappointed and yet also...
心から…
ホッとしていた
profoundly relieved.
The Other House
Among the freshly blooming dandelions
And the droplets of water which couldn't quite become snow
I thought I could make out a face stained with tears
So I offered my umbrella without a second thought
Is going left or right correct?
The path ended before I could really decide
But surely the right call is the one which spares that special someone
From any painful experiences
So with a little courage, take that plunge forward
If everything's all crooked, take an oblique path
As long as you're moving forward, you'll find the light
Like those little birds that huddle together and cry out in unison
We'll definitely ring in the start of a new season
And so spring will embrace us once more
We'll splash paint on some new pages
We became fast friends, we enjoyed some good food
We might've even argued a little
But we carry those little moments in our hearts
As reasons which compel us toward a future that can't possibly be mistaken
No matter how many times we find ourselves lost among sunlit trees
Today has been carried here by the winds on a one-way ticket
That blooms into a perfect day
Child of March City
（ひなた）
“みんなで もんじゃに行こう”
"Let's go to a monjayaki place."
桐山(きりやま)君が誘ってくれた
Kiriyama invited us...
before Takahashi left for Kouchi.
高橋(たかはし)君が 高知へ旅立つ前に
Monja Jirou
Monja
Jirou
（零）それじゃ え〜っと…
Well, um,
both of you, congratulations on graduating.
２人とも 卒業おめでとう
And I wish you the best of luck at the private school in Kouchi.
そして 高橋君の
高知義塾(こうちぎじゅく)での活躍を祈って—
え〜っと かんぱ…
Uh, cheer—
（高橋）
あっ…　ちょっと待ってください
Wait a second.
それから…
Also...
Kiriyama, congratulations on your promotion to B2!
桐山さん
Ｂ２昇級 おめでとうございます
ああ… ありがとう
Thank you!
（ひなた）えっ？　あっ…
お… おめでとう 桐山君
C-Congratulations, Kiriyama!
Just found out
That's amazing!
すごいッス！
Admire
じっちゃんが すげえ喜んでました
My grandpa was so psyched about
personally knowing a B-class shogi player.
知人にＢ級の棋士がいるなんて
Yes!
（高橋の祖父）やった〜！
My teacher made it to Class B!
（高橋）もう みんなに
自慢したくてたまらないみたいで
He was so proud that he couldn't contain himself.
Kiriyama is a future Master!
桐山君は 未来の名人じゃ！
（零）ああ… ありがたい
I appreciate that.
あっ…　じゃ 前回のＮＨＫ杯
早々に負けちゃって すみません
I apologize for losing so quickly at that last NHK Cup.
I know they were really looking forward to it.
すっごく楽しみにしてくれてたのに
Nah, it's fine.
（高橋）
いえいえ　じっちゃんは もう—
Grandpa was like, "Next up is the Lion King Tournament!"
“次は獅子王戦じゃ”って言って
盛り上がってましたから
He's already excited about that.
Thanks for waiting.
（店員）はい お待たせ
鮭(さけ)もんじゃと あと明太餅(めんたいもち)チーズね
Salmon monja and rice cakes with cheese and cod.
Thanks.
（高橋）どうも
Thank you!
（零･ひなた）
ありがとうございます
桐山さんは すっかり
俺のじっちゃんのアイドルですよ
Kiriyama, you're totally my grandpa's idol.
寝込みがちだったのが—
Before he would mostly stay in bed,
but recently he popped in at the neighborhood shogi club.
最近じゃ 近所の将棋クラブにも
また顔を出すようになって
Shogi Club
My parents are both happy that he's back on his feet.
元気出てくれて
親父(おやじ)も おふくろも喜んでいます
They're like, "Pros are incredible!"
“プロって すごいなぁ”って
俺も 早くプロになりたいッス
I want to turn pro soon too.
（ひなた）“プロになりたい”
"I want to turn pro."
Not "someday."
“いつか”ではなく
“早く”と言った
He said "soon."
Oh, I'll do it.
あっ 俺やります
（零）いいの？
（高橋）任せといてください
Are you sure?
Leave it to me.
（ひなた）そうなのだ
高橋君の中で プロは もう—
That's right.
In Takahashi's mind,
turning pro has gone from a dream to a goal.
夢から目標に変わっているのだ
Monja Jirou
Monja
Jirou
（高橋）リトルリーグのころ
お世話になった人が今—
A person who helped me back in little league is now the coach of the school in Kouchi.
高知義塾で監督をやっているんです
東京は 野球の名門に
強いヤツが集中して—
All the best players are concentrated in Tokyo,
and there are a lot of infielders.
内野手の層が厚すぎるんです
しかも
それが何十校もそろっている
On top of that, there are dozens of schools.
俺は 甲子園に出られる確率を
少しでも上げたいんです
I want to raise my chances of making nationals,
even if it's only by a little.
だから
監督のもとへ行くことを決めました
So I decided to go where that coach is.
（ひなた）高橋君の
慣れた手つきで鳴るコテの音で—
With Takahashi's practiced hands and the clanging of the spatula,
いつものようにジュージューと
いい匂いが立ち上る
the familiar sizzling sound and delicious scent rose up.
でも
もうすぐ この春の三月町(さんがつちょう)から—
But this spring,
高橋君は いなくなるのだ
Takahashi will be leaving March City.
高知にも
もんじゃってあるのかな？
I wonder if they have monja in Kouchi.
なくても作れますよ
ホットプレートさえあれば
Even if they don't, I can make it.
All I need is a hot plate.
You can get the ingredients at any supermarket too.
材料なんて
どこのスーパーでも売ってる物(もん)だし
Oh, I'll be bringing some sliced squid, though.
あっ 切りイカは
一応 持っていきますけど
I heard they're having a welcome party at the dorm,
so I thought I'd make this as a greeting.
寮で歓迎会してくれるっていうから
挨拶代わりに作ろうと思うッス
“三月町から来ました”って
Kind of like saying, "I'm from March City."
（ひなた）ああ… そっか
Oh, I see.
私たちは三月町の子だ
We're children of March City.
それだけは絶対に—
No matter where we go,
どこへ行っても変わらない
that'll never change.
うん それいいね！
きっと みんな—
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Even if they know what monja is, they probably haven't tried it yet.
もんじゃは知ってても
まだ食べたことないと思う
うん 高橋君が作るなら
きっと うまいはずだ
Right.
And I'm sure it'll be good if Takahashi makes it.
もちろんッス！
You bet!
あっ でも コテだけは持ってけって
じいちゃんが買ってくれました
Oh, though Grandpa told me to
at least take some spatulas for it.
The bamboo kind to use with hot plates.
ホットプレート用に竹のやつ
Oh, right.
ああ 確かに
They probably don't sell this little kind there,
even if they do have big ones.
この小さいコテは売ってなさそう
大きいのはあっても
（ひなた）
不意に 涙が出そうになった
It suddenly felt like I was going to cry.
彼は 本当に
もうすぐ ここを去るのだ
He really was going to leave this place soon.
何度も泣きそうになって—
I caught myself on the verge of tears a number of times, but I held my breath.
息を止めた
When are you leaving?
（零）いつ行くの？
（高橋）来週の土曜です
Next Saturday.
That's the day of the Cherry Blossom Festival.
（ひなた）桜まつりの日だよ
Yeah.
（高橋）
うん 見れなくて残念だけど
It's a shame that I have to miss it.
川本(かわもと)は また屋台やるの？
Will you do another food stand, Kawamoto?
Yeah.
（ひなた）うん
今回はね お汁粉だよ　２種類
This time we're making two kinds of sweet red bean soup!
（高橋）そっか　頑張れよ
（ひなた）うん
Cool.
Good luck.
Thanks.
（ひなた）この時間が大事で
This time is precious.
でも 流れて—
But it's flowing onward,
止められなくて
and I can't stop it.
零ちゃんが 最後に
いっぱい話せるように誘ってくれて
I'm so happy that Rei invited me,
giving me the chance to talk to Takahashi a lot at the end.
本当に うれしかった
一緒に もんじゃ つつけて
ホントに良かった
It's great that we got to have monja together.
ホントに 良かった
It was great.
そして—
And so, the morning of the Cherry Blossom Festival came.
桜まつりの朝が来ました
Sweet Red
Bean Soup
Azuki
dumplings
Walnut
300 yen
Tea
（あかり）さてと…
All right,
（あかり）準備完了！
preparations complete!
フ〜ン！
そろそろ いきますか！
Shall we get started?
（ひなた）いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome!
Who would like some sweet red bean soup with rice dumplings?
三日月(みかづき)堂の白玉入りのお汁粉
いかがですか？
（女性）あら
今回のも おいしいわ 三日月堂さん
Oh, Crescent Moon is serving up tasty food again.
It's thick, sweet, and salty.
トロッとしてて 甘じょっぱいのね
Good to hear!
良かった！
白味噌(しろみそ)が入ってるんですよ
It has light-brown miso inside.
This warms me up.
温(あった)まるわ
まだまだ川辺は冷えるから
It's still chilly by the riverside.
Oh, then I'll have some sweet red
bean soup with walnut dumplings.
（女性）あら じゃ私も くるみ汁粉
Heavy
Tupperware
containing
the cash made
from sales
Tupperware
containing
the cash made
from sales
よし 好調ね　まだ肌寒いから
温かいのにしたの正解だったわ
Yes, business is booming!
It's still cold outside, so going with
something warm was the right choice!
How's it going?!
（相米二(そめじ)）どうでえ？　調子は
Snort
白玉 足りなくなったら
早めに言えよ
If you start running low on dumplings, let me know!
Snort
I'll boil up as many as we need!
いっくらでも ゆでるぜ！
いざとなったら
合言葉は“黒蜜きな粉”だからな
If that happens, call out the secret phrase, "brown sugar syrup roasted soy flour"!
Got it!
（あかり）了解！
（ひなた）ラジャー！
Roger!
いいの？　お見送り行かなくて
Are you sure you don't want to see him off?
Yes.
うん いいの
It's okay.
（高橋）頑張れよ
Good luck.
よいしょ…
Hup!
（ひなた）
高橋君　私も ここで頑張るね
Takahashi, I'm going to do my best here too.
Excuse me!
（男性）すみません
くるみ白玉２つください
Two bowls of soup with walnut dumplings, please!
Okay!
（ひなた）はい！　いらっしゃい！
Coming right up!
（美咲(みさき)）ええっ！　ひなが髪を？
What? Hina cut her hair?
Wait—
（美咲）…て
乙女の一大イベントじゃないの！
That's a major event in a young girl's life!
Oh no.
そんな…
小さな恋が ひとつ終わって—
Did she cut her hair because a crush was quashed?!
髪を切るだなんて！
That's right!
そうなの！
ゆうべ 急に言いだして
She suddenly told me last night!
キャ〜ッ！　甘酸っぱい！　アア…
It's so bittersweet!
（ひなた）
お姉ちゃん　私 髪切ろうかな
Sis, I'm thinking of getting a haircut.
Huh?
（あかり）えっ？
い… いいんじゃないかしら
S-Sure, why not?
ハッ！
これが もしや伝説の あの…
Is this that legendary...
I will cut my hair to give a proper send-off to my childhood self
I will cut my hair to give a proper send-off to my childhood
self and to take a step forward as the new me.
and to take a step forward as the new me.
I will cut my hair to give a proper send-off to my childhood
self and to take a step forward as the new me.
I could tell she was reading that kind of poem in her head!
I will cut my hair to give a proper send-off to my childhood
self and to take a step forward as the new me.
…ていうポエムを 絶対
心の中で詠んでるのが分かって
I will cut my hair to give a proper send-off to my childhood
self and to take a step forward as the new me.
How can I put it?
何ていうか こう モダモダしちゃう
I'm at a loss!
Oh, jeez!
あ〜 もう…
My little sister is too cute!
かわいすぎる 私の妹が！
This is the springtime of her life!
青春なのね！
Hina!
ひな　もう…　なんて甘酸っぱいの
It's so bittersweet!
Akari, don't you dare say any of that to Hina.
Umm...
あかり
それ 絶対 ひなに言っちゃダメよ
Umm...
I'm sure she'd become so embarrassed that she'd faint.
ひな きっと気絶しちゃうわよ
恥ずかしくて
（戸の開く音）
（あかり）ただいま
I'm home.
ひ〜な　どうだった？
Hina!
How'd it go at the beauty salon?
美容室は…
Gloom
Huh?!
…て どうしたの？
Huh?! What's wrong?!
Gloom
Huh?!
（ひなた）失敗した…
It was a failure.
I'm never leaving the house again.
もう外には出ない
高校も２学期から行く
I'll go to high school when second trimester starts.
H-Here.
ど… どれ？　見せてごらん
Let me take a look.
あ… あら ひな
O-Oh, Hina.
い… いいわよ
I-It looks great!
うん　何ていうか…
Yeah.
How should I say it...
すっかり中学生っぽくなって…
It's a very junior high look...
Shiver
No! I mean...
あっ ちがっ…
えっと…
Shiver
It's such a high school look...
高校生らしくなって…
Shiver
Tiny
うん！　と… とにかく
に… 似合ってる すっごく
Right! A-Anyway, it looks good on you! Really good!
お… 大人っぽく
ボブにしてくださいって言ったのに
I-I asked her to give me an adult-like bob cut...
（ひなた）
お… おばちゃんしかいなくて…
B-But only an old woman was at the salon...
（美容師）ウフッ！
あ〜ら ひなちゃん　ボブ？
Oh, Hina! A bob cut?
Okay. You can count on me.
ＯＫ　任せといて！
The
next
day
The
next
day
Oof...
よいしょっと…
What the hell?!
ダアッ！　何だ！
Oh, Hina?
ひなか…
座敷童子(ざしきわらし)かと思った
I thought it was a household deity!
Wha?!
You can't
say that!
Hey, Grandpa!
こら おじいちゃん！
You can't
say that!
（モモ）ひなちゃん　これ！
Hina!
Here!
I'm not a wooden doll!
こけし違う！
Nooo
Momo, how could you?!
Apparently trying
to cheer her up
Nooo
モモのバカ！
Hina, here!
（モモ）ひなちゃん　これ！
（ひなた）もう外出ない！
I'm never going outside!
Hina!
I'll become a shut-in!
引きこもる〜！
（あかり）
もうダメ！　我慢できない！
I can't hold it in any longer!
Please, Hina!
お願い ひな！
ちょっと これ持ってみて！
Hold this just for a second!
Candy Drops
You too, Sis?!
（ひなた）お姉ちゃんまで！
Hina, please!
（あかり）ひな！
お願い！　１回だけでいいの！
Please, Hina? Just once!
No way!
Come on, Hina!
（あかり）ねっ？　ひな
（モモ）ひなちゃん！
Child of March City
Please!
（あかり）お願い！
Surrounded by a landscape on the verge of permanent stasis
I found myself searching for something
I took up a mask to make my pitifully weak self appear stable
And donned it boldly
The sound of my frozen footsteps as I walked along the river
Was easily overpowered by the roar of a passing train
Yet I kept chanting "I just gotta take another step" to myself
Over and over again
Can you hear me proclaiming that I'm standing right here?
Even in bare feet I can go wherever the hell I want
I don't know where I might find myself at the end
I can't begin to guess, but I can just ink in
A new landscape to suit me as I go
Hina, Kiriyama's come to pick you up.
（あかり）
ひな　桐山君 迎えに来てくれたよ
お〜い　出てこないと
桐山君も遅刻しちゃうよ
Hey!
If you don't come out, Kiriyama is going to be late too.
（あかり）ひな
もう…　観念して出てきなさい
Hina, just resign yourself to it and come out.
Stare
へ… 変でしょう？
し… 失敗しちゃって
I-It's weird, isn't it?
I-I never should've done it.
I-It looks stupid, doesn't it?!
お… おかしいでしょう？
Hawawa
I-I-I really do look like that household deity with the bowl hairstyle!
ややや… やっぱり
座敷童子みたいでしょう？
Wahhh
Yeah, it's nice.
Huh?
Yeah, yeah.
すっごくいい！
It's really nice.
Rei?
零ちゃん…
Yeah, there's something about it.
（零）
うん なんかいい　すっごくいい
I really like it!
（ひなた）へっ？　あの…
（零）超 似合ってる！
What?
Um...
It totally suits you!
（ひなた）あ… あの…
U-Um...
あり …がとう
Thank... you...
Yeah, yeah.
E-Enough already!
も… もういいってば
I like it!
（零）いいねえ！
（ひなた）はわわ…　恥ずかしいよ
You're embarrassing me!
（零）すっごくいいと思う！
（ひなた）もうやめて〜！
I think it's great!
Just stop it!
Illustration: Umino Chika
（零）
「３月のライオン」を
ご覧いただき…
Thank you for watching...
"March comes in like a lion"!
（一同）
ありがとうございました
Let's meet again!
（あかり･ひなた）
また お会いしましょう
Bye-bye!